A Finding Aid to the Marian Locks Gallery Records, 1932, 1968-1991, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Marian Locks Gallery records
1932, 1968-1991
Archives of American Art
Marian Locks Gallery
AAA.marilock
Archival Resource Key
0.6 Linear feet
The records of the Marian Locks Gallery measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1932 and 1968 to 1991. The records document the history of the Philadelphia gallery through exhibition schedules; price lists for one person and group shows; artists' files on Ronald Bateman, Salvatore Pinto, and Gerald Pogach; press releases; and printed material, including 3 issues of ML Newsletter, 1984, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, and newspaper clippings of reviews of shows at the gallery. Among the artists represented are Edna Andrade, Tom Chimes, Ray Metzker, Elizabeth Osborne, and Warren Rohrer.
Biographical / Historical
Marian Locks Gallery was an art gallery in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, established in 1968. The name changed to Locks Gallery around 1990. The gallery mainly showed the work of contemporary Philadelphia area artists.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into one series.
Series 1: Marian Locks Gallery, 1932, 1968-1991 (0.6 linear feet; Boxes 1-2)
Scope and Contents
The records of the Marian Locks Gallery measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1932 and 1968 to 1991. The records document the history of the Philadelphia gallery through exhibition schedules; price lists for one person and group shows; artists' files on Ronald Bateman, Salvatore Pinto, and Gerald Pogach; press releases; and printed material, including 3 issues of ML Newsletter, 1984, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, and newspaper clippings of reviews of shows at the gallery. Among the artists represented are Edna Andrade, Tom Chimes, Ray Metzker, Elizabeth Osborne, and Warren Rohrer.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated 1991 by Marian Locks.
Art galleries, Commercial -- Pennsylvania; Locks, Marian; Bateman, Ronald C., 1947-; Pinto, Salvatore, 1905-1966; Pogach, Gerald
- Marian Locks Gallery records, 1932, 1968-1991; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents
  The records of the Marian Locks Gallery measure 0.6 linear feet and date from 1932 and 1968 to 1991. The records document the history of the Philadelphia gallery through exhibition schedules; price lists for one person and group shows; artists' files on Ronald Bateman, Salvatore Pinto, and Gerald Pogach; press releases; and printed material, including 3 issues of ML Newsletter, 1984, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, and newspaper clippings of reviews of shows at the gallery. Among the artists represented are Edna Andrade, Tom Chimes, Ray Metzker, Elizabeth Osborne, and Warren Rohrer.
  - Ronald Bateman, 1970-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Salvatore Pinto, 1932, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gerald Pogach, 1985-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Schedules, 1969-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Price Lists, 1968-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1969-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10-14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1987-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Newsletters, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reviews, undated, 1968-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6-7)